Guide to the Richard C. Bell Drawings and Other Materials
Richard C. Bell Drawings and Other Materials
- Drawings, 1924-2004
  - King's Pond and Mill at Sedgefield, 1987-1988 (Tube 22)
    Master Site Plan
    Evans Engineering, Inc.; Guilford County (N.C.)
  - Kinston Plaza Shopping Center, 1970 (Tube 69)
    Mall plan, landscape plan
    Bell Richard C. 1928-
  - Kopcsok (Mr. and Mrs. A.A.) residence (Tube 54)
    Preliminary landscape plan
  - Lackey (Mr. and Mrs. W. Ray) residence (1 of 3), 1978 (Tube 263)
    Overall grading, landscape development plan, planting details, landscape construction
    Bell Design Group; Statesville (N.C.)
  - Lackey (Mr. and Mrs. W. Ray) residence (2 of 3), 1978 (Tube 264)
  - Lackey (Mr. and Mrs. W. Ray) residence (3 of 3), 1978 (Tube 458)
    Overall Planting
  - Ladd (Dick and Jean) residence, 1993 (Tube 845)
    Deck Details, Landscape Development Plans
    Bell-Glazener Design Group; Cary (N.C.)
  - Ladd (Mr. and Mrs. Richard) residence, 1977 (Tube 846)
    Foundation and basement Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Elevations, Details, Sections
    Jerry Miller Associates; Cary (N.C.)
  - Lake Ellsworth ("The Lakes"): Property of Wedco II, Inc., 1974-1979 (Tube 788)
    Preliminary Plat and Topographic Survey, Site Plan, Concept Plan
    Dickerson-Adams and Associates; Bell Design Group; Greenville Engineering and Surveying Co.; Greenville (N.C.)
  - Lake Hickory Country Club, 1967 (Tube 702)
    Site Plans, Plans of Pool Area, Grading Plan, Schematic Site Development Plan, Overall Site Development Plan, Layout of Gas Post Lights, Staking Plans, Pool Layout, Cross-sections
    Harrell-Clark & Associates; Richard C. Bell Associates; Hickory (N.C.)
  - Lakes Village ("The Lakes"): Lake Placid Development Co. (Tube 785)
    Concept Plan, Site Plans
  - Lakeside, 1987 (Tube 161)
    Entrance signage
  - Lakewoods (Tube 836)
    Property Maps, Topographic Maps, Soils
    Cramerton Properties, Inc.; Burlington Industries, Inc.; Bell Design Group; Cramerton (N.C.)
  - Lamm (Bessie H. and Virginia Hayes) property, 1982 (Tube 714)
    Site Plans, Aerial Maps
    Piedmont Aerial Surveys, Inc.; Associated Surveys Co.; R. R. Herring & Associates; Wilson County (N.C.)
  - Landmark Center (1 of 2), 1988 (Tube 663)
    Final Plotting
  - Landmark Center (2 of 2), 1988 (Tube 666)
  - Lands West of Atlantic Beach, N.C. (1 of 4), 1976 (Tube 648)
  - Lands West of Atlantic Beach, N.C. (2 of 4), 1976 (Tube 741)
    Land Use and Zoning, Ownership, Summary of Conditions, Soils, Land Assimilation, Sales Parcels without Trades, Land Use, Land Value Existing
    Bennett C. N.; Bell Design Group; Carteret County (N.C.)
  - Lands West of Atlantic Beach, N.C. (3 of 4), 1976 (Tube 742)
    Elevations, Sales Parcels with Trades, Site Plan
    Bell Design Group; Bennett C. N.; Carteret County (N.C.)
  - Lands West of Atlantic Beach, N.C. (4 of 4), 1976 (Tube 768)
    Ownership, Land Use/Zoning, Sales Parcels (with), Elevations, Sales Parcels (without), Summary of Conditions, Soils
  - Landscape Quality Analysis of Shelby, North Carolina (Tube 849)
    Landscape Quality Map Showing: Class 1 Areas; Class 2 Areas; Class 3 Areas; Class 4 Areas; Class 5 Areas
    Richard C. Bell Associates; Murphy C. Crawford Architect; Shelby (N.C.)
  - Latimer residence, 1967 (Tube 200)
  - Latimer residence (Tube 204)
  - Laurel Springs (Tube 690)
    Subdivision Site Plan, Entrance Fence with Sign
    Bell Design Group; Group Six Inc.; Philip Post and Associates Inc.; Orange County (N.C.)
  - Law Enforcement Center, Charlotte, 1967 (Tube 718)
    Planting Detail, Planting Plan, Site Plan
    Richard C. Bell Associates; Graves & Toy; Charlotte (N.C.)
  - Lea (Jim and Diane) residence, 1997-2001 (Tube 119)
    Landscape development plan including house modification, plans and elevations, conceptual plan
  - Lea (Jim and Diane) residence, 1997 (Tube 120)
  - Lea (Jim and Diane) residence (1 of 2), 1967 (Tube 119)
    York, Herman Henry
  - Lea (Jim and Diane) residence (2 of 2), 1967 (Tube 120)
  - Lea (Mr. and Mrs. W.B., Jr.) residence, 1962 (Tube 703)
    Bell Richard C. 1928-; Rocky Mount (N.C.)
  - Lenoir County Hospital (Tube 703)
    Godwin and Bell, A.S.L.A.; Kinston (N.C.)
  - Leslieshire Drive area (Tube 552)
    Plat Map
  - Levy (Mr. and Mrs. Bertram) residence (1 of 2), 1965 (Tube 200)
    Planting plan, master landscape and site development plan
  - Levy (Mr. and Mrs. Bertram) residence (2 of 2), 1965 (Tube 527)
  - Levy (Mr. and Mrs. Bertram) residence, 1966 (Tube 204)
  - Lewis Farm, 1987 (Tube 54)
    Preliminary land-use plan
    Bell Design Group; William C. Piver & Associates; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Lewis Farm residence (Tube 845)
    Water Shed Study, Site Plan
  - Ligget and Meyers Tobacco Company: Proposed administration building, 1965 (Tube 282)
    Preliminary site and landscape plan
    Richard C. Bell Associates; Harris and Pyne; Durham (N.C.)
  - Liggett and Meyers Tobacco Company, 1965-1968 (Tube 280)
    Schematic site plan, changes to landscape plan, plant list
    Harris and Pyne; Richard C. Bell Associates; Durham (N.C.)
  - Lindner (Mr. and Mrs. Donald) residence (1 of 3), 1980-1982 (Tube 743)
    Site Plan, Grading Plan, Staking Plan, Planting Plan, Proposed Pool, Terrace, and Fence Plan, Construction Details, Interior Improvements
    Bell Design Group; High Point (N.C.)
  - Lindner (Mr. and Mrs. Donald) residence (2 of 3), 1980-1982 (Tube 747)
    Details, Garage and Entrance Areas Renovations, Grading Plan
  - Lindner (Mr. and Mrs. Donald) residence (3 of 3), 1980-1982 (Tube 744)
    Topographic Survey Topographic Map
    Davis-Martin-Powell & Associates; Fulbright James C. PE; High Point (N.C.)
  - Lindner (Mr. and Mrs. Donald) residence, 1982 (Tube 845)
    Site Plan, Landscape Design, Garage and Entrance Area Renovations
  - Lindner (Mr. and Mrs. Donald) residence, 1987 (Tube 846)
    William F. Freeman Associates, Architects; High Point (N.C.)
  - Litchfield Plantation, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Compass Survey
    Georgetown County (S.C.)
  - Litchfield Plantation (Tube 1)
  - Litchfield Plantation: Club and office facility (Tube 703)
    Water Distribution and Sewage Plan, Planting Plan, Plant List and Details, Elevation, Site Plan, Floor Plan
  - Little Maryknoll residence of the Bishop, Diocese of Raleigh, 1961-1962 (Tube 204)
  - Little Maryknoll residence of the Bishop, Diocese of Raleigh, 1961 (Tube 459)
  - Little Maryknoll residence of the Bishop, Diocese of Raleigh, 1962 (Tube 200)
  - Little (Dr.) residence (Tube 496)
    Terrace plan
  - Little (Dr. and Mrs. H.R., Jr.) residence, 1967-1969 (Tube 200)
    Preliminary landscape plan, site details for landscaping plan, planting plan
    Richard C. Bell Associates; New Bern (N.C.)
  - Lockhaven and Burtrose subdivisions, 1963-1964 (Tube 736)
    Lockhaven: Plantings, 2409 Tri-Level Elevations, 2409 First Floor Plan, 2027 Two Story Foundation Plan and Sections, 2027 Floor Plans, Elevations, 1882 Tri-Level Floor Plans and Elevations, Elevation Study, Master Site Development, Lots 1-11; Burtrose: Plans and Elevations (Split-Level Unit), Single Floor Unit Plans and Elevations, Split Foyer Unit Plans and Elevations, Site Plans
    Sugg Jefferson L.; Moore, Gardner and Associates, Inc.; Richard C. Bell Associates; Cary (N.C.)
  - Long, Haymes & Carr, Inc., 1983 (Tube 577)
    Planting, elevations, floor plans, site location map
    Cundiff & Associates, CPA; Bell-Glazener Design Group; Winston-Salem (N.C.)
  - Long, Haymes & Carr, Inc. (Tube 578)
    Signage
  - Long, Haymes & Carr, Inc.: Corporate headquarters, 1989 (Tube 507)
    Master Landscape Improvement Plans
  - Long, Haymes & Carr, Inc.: Corporate headquarters (1 of 2), 1990 (Tube 761)
    Staking
  - Long, Haymes & Carr, Inc.: Corporate headquarters (2 of 2), 1990 (Tube 759)
    Planting, grading and drainage, building entrances, details, master landscape improvements plan, demolition
    Bell-Glazener Design Group; Cundiff & Associates, CPA; Winston-Salem (N.C.)
  - Lost Colony Housing Area (1 of 2), 1969 (Tube 529)
    Entrance drive
    Richard C. Bell Associates; Roanoke Island (N.C.)
  - Lost Colony Housing Area (2 of 2), 1969 (Tube 527)
    Details, entrance drive, master landscape plan
  - Lost Colony Housing Area: Roanoke Island Historical Association, 1969 (Tube 263)
    Master landscape plan and details
  - Lowry (Mr. and Mrs. Britton) residence: Litchfield Plantation (1 of 2), 1969 (Tube 200)
    Site development plan - lighting, overall landscaping, interior gardens, construction details
  - Lowry (Mr. and Mrs. Britton) residence: Litchfield Plantation (2 of 2), 1969 (Tube 204)
    Site Development plan
  - Lucas (C. Clement, Jr.) property (Tube 282)
  - Lucas (Dr. and Mrs. C. Clement) residence, 1974-1977 (Tube 271)
    Plant list, planting notes, planting details, grading
  - Lucas (Dr. and Mrs. C. Clement, Jr.) residence: Sycamore Farm, 1974-1978 (Tube 279)
    Construction details, project planting plan
  - Lucas (Dr. and Mrs. Clement) residence (Tube 469)
  - Lyday (Mr. and Mrs. R.O., Jr.) residence, 1965 (Tube 704)
    Details, Staking Plans, Planting Plans, Grading Plans
  - Lyerly residence, 2001 (Tube 145)
    Phase 2 first floor renovations
    Peterman Ken; Chapel Hill (N.C.)
  - Lyerly (Kim and Annie) residence (1 of 2), 2002 (Tube 426)
    Lighting plan, staking/grading plan, master plan, topographic survey, construction details, planting plan
  - Lyerly (Kim and Annie) residence (2 of 2), 2002 (Tube 428)
  - Lynndale East Subdivision Phase I, 1991-1997 (Tube 539)
    Site and Utility Improvement Plans
  - Lyons (Gil) residence (Tube 201)
    Staking and grading plans, planting plan, planting details, existing conditions, construction details
  - MacBradshaw (Tom and Mary) residence (Tube 145)
  - Macedonia Methodist Church, 1962 (Tube 494)
  - Magnolia Seashore Area, 1960 (Tube 270)
    Conservation-recreation use study
    Simmons Kenneth B. FASLA; Georgetown County (S.C.)
  - Major (Andrew and Flora) residence (1 of 3), 1983 (Tube 743)
    Conceptual Plans
  - Major (Andrew and Flora) residence (2 of 3), 1983 (Tube 769)
  - Major (Andrew and Flora) residence (3 of 3), 1983 (Tube 744)
    Survey
    Young Robert W. Land Surveyor; Durham (N.C.)
  - Map of major highways in Southeastern States (Tube 66)
  - Marina Village (1 of 2), 1974 (Flatfolder 7)
    Atlantic Beach (N.C.)
  - Marina Village (2 of 2), 1974 (Flatfolder 8)
  - Marine Corps Chapel (Tube 692)
    Preliminary Master Plan, Entrance and Courtyards
    Bell Design Group; RWC, Inc.; Camp Lejeune (N.C.)
  - Marine Exchange, 1975 (Tube 575)
    Bell Design Group; Willis James B. Jr.
  - Marine Exchange (Tube 580)
  - Marist Society apartment complex (Tube 175)
  - Market Plaza (1 of 2), 1966-1983 (Tube 155)
    Construction details, preliminary landscape drawings, details, specifications
    Bell Design Group; Williams F. Carter Fred Carter 1913-2000; Richard C. Bell Associates; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Market Plaza (2 of 2), 1966-1983 (Tube 154)
    Staking plan, grading plan, preliminary landscape design, general notes, irrigation details, paving patterns, topographic survey
    Richard C. Bell Associates; Bell Design Group; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Market Street Apartments, 1973 (Tube 796)
    Land Use Study #1
  - Marshall (Dr. and Mrs. Penn) residence (1 of 3), 1966 (Tube 54)
  - Marshall (Dr. and Mrs. Penn) residence (2 of 3), 1966 (Tube 571)
  - Marshall (Dr. and Mrs. Penn) residence (3 of 3), 1966 (Tube 572)
    Details, landscape plan
  - Martin and Lincolnton Street parks, 1973 (Tube 250)
  - Martin (Mr. and Mrs. Albert C.) residence, 1965 (Tube 494)
  - Martin (Mr. and Mrs. R.W.) residence, 1964 (Tube 493)
    Schematic plan, preliminary landscape plan
  - Matthes (Mr. and Mrs. Donald G.) residence, 1968-1971 (Tube 796)
    Landscape Plans, Landscape Details, Preliminary Landscape Plan, Planting Plan, Grading and Staking Plan
    Shields-Wyatt Architects; Cogswell Hausler Associates; Richard C. Bell Associates; Chapel Hill (N.C.)
  - Matthews (Dick and Alice) residence, 1993 (Tube 291)
    Landscape plan, details of loft study
  - Maxwell Garden Center, 1962 (Tube 50)
  - May property, 1971-1972 (Tube 321)
    Richard C. Bell Associates; Burlington (N.C.)
  - May (John) topographic survey, 1999 (Tube 486)
    Pinehurst (N.C.)
  - May's Lake (Tube 758)
    Grading and storm drainage, site utilities, electrical plan
    Ligon B. Flynn Associates; Richard C. Bell Associates; Burlington (N.C.)
  - McClees (Mr. and Mrs. Tom) residence, 1961 (Tube 493)
    Staking and construction plan, construction details, planting plan
    Bell Richard C. 1928-; Elm City (N.C.)
  - McDonald (Katherine) residence (1 of 2), 1962 (Tube 493)
    Bell Richard C. 1928-; Cameron (N.C.)
  - McDonald (Katherine) residence (2 of 2), 1962 (Tube 494)
  - McLaney (Mr. and Mrs. George) residence, 1975 (Tube 575)
    Landscape development plan, staking, grading, planting, details
    Bell Design Group; Elizabethtown (N.C.)
  - McLaney (Mr. and Mrs. George) residence (Tube 580)
  - McLarry (Michael and Louise) residence (Tube 692)
  - Meadowbrook Mall L.L.C., 1992 (Tube 311)
    Gupton-Foster Associates, PA; Forsyth County (N.C.)
  - Meadowbrook Manor (1 of 2), 1982 (Tube 508)
    Ray Troxell Associates, Inc.; Bell Design Group; Clemmons (N.C.)
  - Meadowbrook Manor (2 of 2), 1982 (Tube 692)
    Identification Sign Renovation, Irrigation Plan, Grading Plan, Details, Details-Planting, Planting Plan, Site Plan, Construction Details
  - Meadowbrook Terrace, 1992 (Tube 322)
    Ray Troxell Associates, Inc.; Clemmons (N.C.)
  - Meadowmont of Chapel Hill, 2000 (Tube 451)
    Cottage Home Floor plans and Elevations
    Small Kane Architects PA; Chapel Hill (N.C.)
  - Meadowmont of Chapel Hill, 2001 (Tube 229)
    Rendering of "Rosemary C" cottage
  - Mecklenburg County Jail, 1969 (Tube 730)
    Freeman-White Architects, Inc.; Richard C. Bell Associates; Charlotte (N.C.)
  - Medfield Estates (Tube 796)
    Subdivision Development Plans
  - Medfield-Kingsbrook Recreation Facility, 1970-1971 (Tube 797)
    Master Development Plans, Site Plan, Grading Plan, Swimming Pool Details and Sections, Bath House Details
  - Meekins (Captain and Mrs. Roger) residence, 1965 (Tube 801)
  - Memorial Hospital of Alamance County, 1980-1981 (Tube 842)
    Existing Conditions, Grading Plan, Planting Plans, Site Plans, Construction Details
    Thompson David; Holloway-Reeves; Bell Design Group; Burlington (N.C.)
  - Meredith College, 1961-1965 (Tube 11)
  - Meredith College, 1961-1969 (Tube 857)
    Future College Union Building Site Study, Enlarged Staking and Grading Plan, Proposed Carlyle Campbell Library - Preliminary Landscape Plan, Landscape Plan, Site Development Plan, Study: Proposed Patio for Alumnae House, Amphitheater Profiles, Planting Plan, Schematic Land-Use Map, Typical Planter Section, Proposed Sanitary Sewer
    Haskins & Rice, Architects; Richard C. Bell Associates; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Meredith College, 1963-1969 (Tube 12)
  - Meredith College (1 of 2), 1980 (Tube 744)
    Master Plan Update
  - Meredith College (2 of 2), 1980 (Tube 746)
    Master Plan Phase I, Site Plans, Master Plan Update, Master Plan for Chapel Area, Existing Conditions
  - Meredith College, 1980-1981 (Tube 742)
    Detailed Planting Plan, Master Plan for Chapel Area Planting Plan, Master Plan Update, Details, Site Plan
    Wood & Cort, PA; Bell Design Group; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Meredith College: Amphitheater and recreation area (1 of 3), 1963 (Tube 56)
    Plans and details
  - Meredith College: Amphitheater and recreation area (2 of 3), 1963 (Tube 204)
  - Meredith College: Amphitheater and recreation area (3 of 3), 1963 (Tube 602)
    Amphitheater Plan and Details
  - Meredith College: Amphitheater and recreation area, 1963-1968 (Tube 200)
    Planting plan, paving details
  - Meredith College: Amphitheater, North Campus, Poteat Dormitory, stable, 1965-1969 (Tube 57)
  - Meredith College: Master plan, 1968 (Tube 35)
  - Meredith College: Master plan 1968/1969 (Tube 855)
    Main Entrance Treatment Plan, Site Plans, Supplementary Lighting Plan Reforestation Planting Plan Phase I, Master Grading Plan, Phase 5, Phase 2, Preliminary Plan and Details of Underpass, Lighting Plans
  - Meredith College: Proposed patio for Alumnae house, 1968 (Tube 56)
  - Meredith College: Stable and amphitheater areas, 1965-1968 (Tube 708)
    Stable: Elevations, Foundation Plan, Sections and Details, Loft Plan, Plumbing Plan, Floor Plan with Electrical Work, Structural Revision, Feasibility Study, Floor Plan; Amphitheater and Recreation Area-Construction Details
    Richard C. Bell Associates; Flynn Ligon B. AIA; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Merki (Don and Betsy) residence (1 of 7), 2003 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Notes, elevations
    Bell-Glazener-Jenkins Planning; Triangle Residential Designs Inc.; Andy Mcdonald Design Group; Chapel Hill (N.C.)
  - Merki (Don and Betsy) residence (2 of 7), 2003 (Tube 134)
    Grading plan
  - Merki (Don and Betsy) residence (3 of 7), 2003 (Tube 137)
    Preliminary study copy, grading plan, site plan
    Bell-Glazener-Jenkins Planning; Triangle Residential Designs Inc.; Chapel Hill (N.C.)
  - Merki (Don and Betsy) residence (4 of 7), 2003 (Tube 586)
    Site Plans, Grading Plans, Floor Plans, Contour Plans, Sketch; Elevations
  - Merki (Don and Betsy) residence (5 of 7), 2003 (Tube 587)
    Site Plans, Grading Plans, Floor Plans, Contour Plans, Elevations
  - Merki (Don and Betsy) residence (6 of 7), 2003 (Tube 588)
    Map Enlargement
    Andy Mcdonald Design Group; Triangle Residential Designs Inc.; Bell-Glazener-Jenkins Planning; Chapel Hill (N.C.)
  - Merki (Don and Betsy) residence (7 of 7), 2003 (Tube 589)
  - Methodist Retirement Home, Inc., 1976 (Tube 304)
    Planting, details and plant list, storm drainage and stabilizations, additions
  - Methodist Retirement Village (1 of 2), 1976 (Tube 300)
    Exterior site work, planting, grading and layout
  - Methodist Retirement Village (2 of 2), 1976 (Tube 303)
    Exterior plant list, construction details
  - Mewborn (Mr. and Mrs. R.E. (Sam)) property, 1976 (Tube 111)
    Land use analysis, proposed subdivision, map of record - land of K.R. Tunstall 1948
  - Mewborn (Mr. and Mrs. R.E. (Sam)) property, 1976 (Tube 112)
    Proposed subdivision
  - Mideastern Construction Company: New office (Tube 182)
  - Mill Creek: Planned recreation area (1 of 4), 1981 (Tube 303)
    Bell Design Group; Devotion (N.C.)
  - Mill Creek: Planned recreation area (2 of 4), 1981 (Tube 735)
    Title Page, Master Plan: Section 1, Tar Ridge Master Plan, Saddle Mountain Master Plan
  - Mill Creek: Planned recreation area (3 of 4), 1981 (Tube 808)
  - Mill Creek: Planned recreation area (4 of 4), 1981 (Tube 811)
  - Mill Creek: Planned recreation area (Tube 286)
  - Mill Run, 1976 (Tube 123)
    Alternative system, site plan, exposure study, site design, slope design, soil study, vegetation study
    Williams D. C.
  - Millbrook Elementary School, 1975 (Tube 160)
    Grading and storm drainage plan
    Smith-Mills Architects; Bell Design Group; Wake County (N.C.)
  - Millbrook School (1 of 2), 1963 (Tube 454)
    Revision No. 1 Site Work
    Jesse M. Page & Associates; Richard C. Bell Associates; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Millbrook School (2 of 2), 1963 (Tube 718)
  - Miller (Larry and Sue) estate: Cloverdale Farm (1 of 3), 1976 (Tube 288)
    Master plan, lighting, irrigation
  - Miller (Larry and Sue) estate: Cloverdale Farm (2 of 3), 1976 (Tube 291)
    Details, sections
    Bell Design Group; Calvert, Lewis & Smith; Halifax County (Va.)
  - Miller (Larry and Sue) estate: Cloverdale Farm (3 of 3), 1976 (Tube 751)
    Grading, staking
  - Miller (Mr. and Mrs. B.H.) residence, 1961 (Tube 494)
  - Martin Marietta Aggregates Pomona Quarry 41-5: Mine map, 1982 (Tube 22)
    William G. Daniel & Associates; Guilford County (N.C.)
  - Mingo Creek (1 of 2), 1985 (Flatfolder 15)
    Bell Design Group; Knightdale (N.C.)
  - Mingo Creek (2 of 2), 1985 (Tube 320)
    Existing conditions map
  - Mitchell (Mr. and Mrs. J.C.) residence (Tube 493)
    Plant list, planting notes
  - Mitchell (Mr. and Mrs. John C.) residence, 1967 (Tube 478)
  - Mitchell (Mr. and Mrs. John C.) residence (Tube 494)
  - Mohican Mills: Lincolnton Plant, 1969 (Tube 801)
    Richard C. Bell Associates; Lincolnton (N.C.)
  - Monk (Bob and Suellen) residence, 1996 (Tube 37)
    modified Site Plan
  - Monk (Mr. and Mrs. A.C., Jr.) residence, 1986 (Tube 71)
  - Monk (Mr. and Mrs. R.T.) property (Tube 362)
    Planting study
    Williams Morley J. A.S.L.A.; Farmville (N.C.)
  - Monk (Mr. and Mrs. Robert T.) residence (Tube 602)
    Foundation Plan and Details, Sections and Exterior Details, Second Floor Plans, Elevations, Wall Details
    Griffith James W. Jr. Architect; Farmville (N.C.)
  - Monk (Mr. and Mrs. Robert T.) residence, 1969-1970 (Tube 72)
  - Monk (Mr. and Mrs. W.C.) residence, 1990 (Tube 72)
    Bell-Glazener Design Group; Farmville (N.C.)
  - Monk (Mr. and Mrs. W.C.) residence, 1964 (Tube 70)
    Plans, elevations, details
    Burgess & Smart; Farmville (N.C.)
  - Monk (Mr. and Mrs. W.C.) residence, 1964-1991 (Tube 71)
    Plans
    Bell-Glazener Design Group; Burgess & Smart; Farmville (N.C.)
  - Monk (Robert, Jr.) residence, 1983 (Tube 37)
  - Montague Building (Tube 437)
    City Planning and Architectural Associates (Chapel Hill, N.C.); Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Moore Square Historic District Streetscape (1 of 2), 1988 (Tube 238)
    Lu & Sears Associates; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Moore Square Historic District Streetscape (2 of 2), 1988 (Tube 625)
    Phase Two B - Phase III Plans
  - Moore Square Station Transit Mall (Tube 872)
  - Moore Square West, 1985 (Tube 437)
  - Moore Square West parking facility, 1987-1988 (Tube 186)
    Bell-Glazener Design Group; Wilbur Smith Associates, Inc.; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Moore Square West Transit Block (1 of 4), 1983 (Tube 623)
    Phase II B Master Plan B
  - Moore Square West Transit Block (2 of 4), 1983 (Tube 253)
    Master plan, block sections, elevations, map, schematic design
    Bell Design Group; Wilbur Smith Associates, Inc.; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Moore Square West Transit Block (3 of 4), 1983 (Tube 254)
    Detailed sections and elevations, site plan, block sections
  - Moore Square West Transit Block (4 of 4), 1983 (Tube 625)
    Functional Plan/Development Concept Phase One Site Plan, Topographic Map
    Raleigh (N.C.) Engineering Department; Wilbur Smith Associates, Inc.; Planning and Design Associates, PA; Bell Design Group; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Moore Square West Transit Block, 1983-1986 (Tube 344)
    Phase II B master plan, toilets, storm, soil, waste and vent piping, plumbing plan, transit block site lighting, bus lane, ground level, elevated walkway, under garage lighting plan, diagram and fixture schedule, walkway stair, ventilation plans and equipment schedule
    Bell Design Group; Planning and Design Associates, PA; Raleigh (N.C.)
  - Moore Square West Transit Block, 1986 (Tube 96)
  - Moore Square West Transit Block: Master Plan B (Tube 439)
  - Moore Square West Transit Mall (1 of 2), 1986 (Tube 342)
    Index of drawings, phasing and alternates, staking, grading, sediment and erosion control, irrigation, plantings, details, grading details
  - Moore Square West Transit Mall (2 of 2), 1986 (Tube 343)
    Details, Hargett Street faade, ticket booth, toilets, floor plans and details, elevation sections, elevated walkway
  - Morehead City Harbor map (Tube 320)
  - Morganton Housing Authority: Low Rent Housing Project, 1969 (Tube 164)
    Harrell-Clark & Associates; Richard C. Bell Associates; Morganton (N.C.)
  - Morganton Housing Authority: Low Rent Housing Project NC 49-1 (Tube 760)
  - Morganton Housing Authority: Low Rent Housing Project NC 49-2 (1 of 2), 1966-1969 (Tube 755)